Guide to the Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine Office of Educational Development records, 1994-2001
Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine Office of Educational Development records, 1994-2001
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University College of Veterinary Medicine Office of Educational Development records, 1994-2001
24-11-3312
Cornell University. College of Veterinary Medicine. Office of Educational Development.
3.0 cubic ft.
Academic guides
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Tutor guides and course guides created to facilitate course instruction at the College of Veterinary Medicine. Produced as part of the problem-based learning curriculum initiated in 1993.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Office of Educational Development at Cornell University's College of Veterinary Medicine was established in 1990. Its stated mission is "to provide leadership and support in the creation and maintenance of educational resources and environments by translating ideas, demonstrating possibilities, anticipating needs, [and] enabling interactions to promote the optimal education of our students." The purpose of the office is to assist with the "development, implementation and maintenance" of the College's educational programming, including the problem-based learning curriculum.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Tutor guides and course guides created by the Office of Educational Development at Cornell University's College of Veterinary Medicine. These guide were created as part of the problem-based learning curriculum initiated in 1993. Their purpose is to facilitate course instruction.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University--College of Veterinary Medicine--Office of Educational Development
Subjects:
Veterinary Medicine--Study and teaching; Problem-based learning
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the Tutor Guides is restricted to the office of origin.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Organized alphabetically by course title.
SERIES LIST
SERIES I. TUTOR GUIDES [RESTRICTED]
Animal Body
Function and Dysfunction
Genetics and Development
Host, Agent and Defense
SERIES II. COURSE GUIDES
Animal Body
Animal Health and Disease
Animals, Veterinarians and Society
Function and Dysfunction
Genetics and Development
Host, Agent and Defense
Practice Management, Hospital Administration and Professional Development
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Tutor Guides
  - Animal Body
    - 1998, folder 1 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1998, folder 2 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1999, folder 1 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1999, folder 2 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Function and Dysfunction
    - 1994 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1995 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Spring 1998, folder 1 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Spring 1998, folder 2 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Fall 1998 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Spring 1999, folder 1 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Spring 1999, folder 2 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Fall 1999, folder 1 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Fall 1999, folder 2 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Spring 2000, folder 1 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Spring 2000, folder 2 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Fall 2000, folder 1 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Fall 2000, folder 2 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Spring 2001, folder 1 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Spring 2001, folder 2 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Genetics and Development
    - 1994 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1999, folder 1 [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1999, folder 2 [RESTRICTED] (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 2000, folder 1 [RESTRICTED] (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 2000, folder 2 [RESTRICTED] (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Host, Agent and Defense
    - 1994, folder 1 [RESTRICTED] (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1994, folder 2 [RESTRICTED] (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1998, folder 1 [RESTRICTED] (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1998, folder 2 [RESTRICTED] (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1999, folder 1 [RESTRICTED] (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1999, folder 2 [RESTRICTED] (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - 2000, folder 1 [RESTRICTED] (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - 2000, folder 2 [RESTRICTED] (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 2001, folder 1 [RESTRICTED] (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - 2001, folder 2 [RESTRICTED] (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Series II. Course Guides
  - Animal Body
    - 1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1998, folder 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1998, folder 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 2000 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Animal Health and Disease
    - 1995, folder 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 1995, folder 2 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Animals, Veterinarians and Society
    - VIIa. Physical Examination, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 517. Physical Examination, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 527. Biomedical Ethics and Clinical Genetics, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 537. Client Interviewing and Communication Skills, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 537. Client Interviewing and Communication Skills, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 538. Diversity and Information Management, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - 538. Information Management and Diversity, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 547. Health Maintenance and Veterinary Clinical Public Health, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - 547. Health Maintenance and Veterinary Clinical Public Health, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - 557. Professional Regulation, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - 557. Professional Regulation, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Function and Dysfunction
    - Spring 1998 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Fall 1998 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Genetics and Development
    - 1999 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - 2000 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Host Agent and Defense
    - 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1999 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 2000 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 2001 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Practice Management, Hospital Administration and Professional Development
    - 1999 (Box 4, Folder 5)